DEPENPENCY (----->)
==========
	- Is the least formal of them all.
	- Means that "class A" uses "class B", but that class A does not contain an instance of "class B" as part
	  of its own state.

	classA ------> classB

	import B;
	
	public class A { public void method1 (B b) }

ASSOCIATION (────────>)
============
	- Association defines dependency, but a much stronger dependency than that described above.
	- There is no ownership between the objects and both have their own lifecycle. Both can create and delete independently.
	- Multiple students can associate with single teacher, and single student can associate with multiple teachers.
	

	classA ────────> classB

AGGREGATION
==============
	- It is a specialised form of Association.
	- There is ownership and child objects can not belong to another parent object.
	- We can think about it as a “has-a” relationship.
	- ejm: A single teacher can not belong to multiple departments, but if we delete the department,
	  teacher object will not be destroyed

	Department ◊─────── Teacher

COMPOSITION
============

	- It is again specialised form of Aggregation
	- Child object does not have its lifecycle and if parent object is deleted, all child objects will also be deleted.

	- ejm: House can contain multiple rooms - there is no independent life of room and any room can not 
	  belong to two different houses. If we delete the house - room will automatically be deleted

	- ejm 2: Single questions can have multiple options and option can not belong to multiple questions. 
	  If we delete questions options will automatically be deleted.
	
		Question ■─────── Option


COMPOSITION ASSOCIATION

	- The instantiation of the linked objects is often hard coded inside the constructor of the object.
	- it cannot be set from outside the object (Composition cannot be a many-to-many relationship).
	- ejm: A House is composed of Stones: House ◊────────> Stone