INTRODUCTION AND OVERVIEW
=========================
	- This lesson is about object orientation and other related concepts.
	- In the first part we will provice a quick introduction to object orientation and object oriented analysis and design.
	- In the second part we will cover the essentials of UML.

OBJECTO ORIENTATION INTRODUCTION
================================
	- What is object orientation?
		- Before object orientation became prevalent, people were not used to thinkin in terms of objects.
		  What does it mean to think in terms of objects and to follow and object-oriented approach?

		- First of all, it means to give "precedence of data over functions". Data ites rather than functionality became
		  the center of the activities. this also allows for enforcing the very important concept of "information hiding"
	  	  which is the "encapsulation and segregation of data"  behind a well-defined and ideally stable interface. In order
		  to be able to hide the design and also implementation decisions.

		  The term encapsulation and information hiding are often used interchangeably, although some people prefer to thinf
		  of information hiding as being the principle and encapsulation being the technique to achieve information hiding.

		  The key concept is really to gather, to seclude this data behind sort of a wall and give acces to the data only through
		  interfaces that you, the developer define. and why is that important? 
		  
		  For many reasons, and one of the main ones is that
		  it makes code more maintainable. Because the rest of the code, the rest of the system doesn't have to be concerned on how
		  the implementation details or the desing are defined. and therefore, any change that happens behind this wall doesn't concern
		  the rest of the system and doesn't affect the rest of the system, as long as you keep your interfaces consistent.

		  Another advantage of focusing on objects and encapsulation the information into cohesive entities is that it allows the reuse
		  of object definitions by incremental refinement, which is normally called inheritance. And inheritance is definetly a fundamental
		  concept in object orientation. Ejm: we can define car as a refinement of the vehicle, that there's some aditional characteristics 
		  with respect to a generic vehicle. And then we can use the car wherever a vehicle can be used, which is what we call polymorphism.

OBJECT AND CLASES
=================
	* Object
		- An object is a computing unit organized around a collection of state or instance variables that define the state of the object.
	  	  In addition, each object has associated with it a set of operations or methods that operate on such state. So what that means is that		  
		  operations and methods read and write instance variables. And in traditional object orientation, we say that operations are invoked by
	  	  sending a message to the appropiate object, which is what we call normally a method implication
	* Class
		- A class is basically a template or a blueprint, from which new objects, which is what we call instances of the class can be created, and
		  notice that the fact of having a blueprint for objects that allows us to create as many objects as we want can further reuse, and also
		  contribute to make the code more readable, understandable and therefore more maintainable.
BENEFITS OF OO
==============
	- Reduce maintenance costs by limiting the effects of changes thanks to encapsulation and information hiding.
	- Improve development process by favoring code and design reuse.
	- Enforce good design. Principles as the ones that we saw in encapsulation, information hiding 

OBJECT ORIENTED ANALYSIS AND DESIGN (OOAD)
===========================================
	- The use of object orientation and object oriented concepts led to what we call OOAD, Object Oriented Analysis and Design.
	- OOAD is a software engineering approach whose main characteristics is to model a software system as a group of interacting 
	  objects.
	- Object oriented analysis is a "requirements analysis technique" that concentrates on modeling real world objects 

OO Analysis Overview
====================
	- traditional analysis and design techniques were "functionally oriented". What that means is that they concentrated on the
	  functions to be perfomed, whereas the data upon which the functions operated were secondary to the functions themselves.
	- Conversely, object oriented analysis, is primarily concerned with the data objects, so we went from a "functional oriented view" to a 
	  "data oriented view", what that means is that during the analysis phase, we define a system first in terms of the data types
	  and their relationships, and the functions or methods are defined only later and associated with specific objects which are sets of data.

	- So the basic idea is to be focused on the objects of the real world. So to go from a real world object to a set of requirements.
	  And we can describe this as a four-step process.
		1. The first step is to obtain or prepare a textual description of the problem to be solved. We need to start from some
		   description of the system we need to build.
		2. The next thing we do is that we take the description and we underline nouns, and the nouns that we underline will became 
		   classes in my analysis.
		3. We the look at adjectives in the document, we underline those, and we use that information to identify the attributes of the
		   classes that we have previously identified.
		4. At this point we focus on active verbs in the description, and the analysis of the active verbs will give us the operations
		   that we we'll need to define our classes.

UML STRUCTURAL DIAGRAMS: CLASS DIAGRAM
========================================
	- Structural diagrams are the diagrams that represent static characteristics of the system that we need to model. This is in
	  contrast with dynamic models which instead represent behaviors of the system that we need to model.
	- The class diagram represents static, structural view of the system, and it describes the classes and their structure, 
	  and relationships among classes.


(incompleto)


CLASS DIAGRAM: RELATIONSHIPS
=============================

	- Describe interactions between clases or between objects in the system. There are three main types of relationships:
		1. Dependency: X uses Y ------------->
		2. Association/Aggregation: X has a Y or X contains a Y
			association: ────────────────
			aggregation: ────────────────◊
		3. Generalization: X is a Y (inheritance) ─────────────>

CLASS DIAGRAM: DEPENDENCY RELATIONSHIP
=======================================
	- 

CLASS DIAGRAM: ASSOCIATION AND AGREGATION RELATIOSHIPS
=======================================================
	* Association
		- This is a relationship in which objects of one class are connected to objects of another. And it's called "has a relationship".
		  So it means that objects of one class have objects of another class. 
	* Aggregation
		- An aggregation is relatioship between 2 classes in which 1 represents a larger class, like a whole which
		  consists of smaller classes. 

CLASS DIAGRAM: GENERALIZATION RELATIONSHIP
===========================================
	- Is a relationship, between a general class (superclass) and the more specific class (sub-class), a class that refines the super-class.

UML STRUCTURAL DIAGRAMS: COMPONENT DIAGRAM
===========================================
	- The component diagram is a static view of the components in a system and of their relationship. 
	- A node in a component diagram represents a component where a component consists of one or more classes with a well defined interface.
	- Edges conversely indicate relationship between the components. We can read this relationship as "Component A uses services of component B".
	- Component diagrams can be used to represent an architecture.
	- Ver ejemplo de udacity.

UML STRUCTURAL DIAGRAMS: DEPLOYMENT DIAGRAM
============================================
	- 

UML BEHAVIORAL DIAGRAMS: USE CASE 
==================================
	* A use case represents two main things:
		- First, the sequence of interactions of outside entities which is what we normally call actors with the system that we're modeling
		- The second thing is the system actions that yield an observable result of values to the actors.
	  Basically this two things, and nothing else than the outside view of the system. So the view of the system in which we look at the interaction
	  between the system and the outside world.
	- Tambien se les llama escenarios, historias de usuario pero en UML son casos de uso.

USE CASE DIAGRAMS: ACTORS
==========================
	- An actor represents and entity, which can be a human or a device, that plays a role within the system or interacts with the system.
	- An entity can play more than one role .
	- Actors may appear in more than one use case.

BUILDING A USE CASE DIAGRAM
============================

   * Documenting use cases:
	- The behavior of a use case can be specified by describing its "flow of events". It should be described from an actor's
	  point of view.
	- the description must detail "what the system must provide to the actor" when the use case is executed. It should describe
	  how the use case starts and ends.
	- It should describe the normal flow of events , what is the normal interaction. ejm: insert card, provide ping...
	- It should also describe possibly "alternative flows of events", in case in which there are multiple ways of accomplishing one action
	  or performing a task. ejm: insert card, provide ping, ask for some information about how much money is in my account.
	- Finally, it should also describe "exceptional flow of events". ejm: insert card, provide wrong ping...

   * The description of the use case can be provided in two main ways: informal and formal way:
	- In the case of an informal description, we could do a textual description of the flow events in natural language.
	- In the case of a formal or structured description, we could use "pre and post conditions", "pseudo-code", "sequence diagrams".
	
	
USE CASE EXAMPLE
================
	- ver video en udacity.

ROLE OF USE CASES
==================
	- why use cases are so important? what are the different roles that use cases can play?
	1. The first obvious one is for requirements elicitation. It is much easier to describe what a system should do if we think
	  about the system in terms of scenarios of usage, rather than trying to describe the whole functionality of the system at once.

	2. Second, they can be used for architectural analysis. use cases are the starting point for the analysis of the architecture of the system
	  that can help identify the main blocks of the system, and therefore can help to define the initial architecture.	

	3. They can be used for user prioritazion. ...define which part of the system should be built in which order.
	   They can be used for planning, if we know which pieces of functionality i need to build and in which order, i can better plan the
	   development of the system.
	
	4. Finally, use cases can be used for testing. if we have an early description of what the system should do, what are the main pieces of 
	   functionality of the system and i know how the interaction between the actors and the system is, we can easily define test cases, even
	   before writing the code.

USE CASE DIAGRAM: CREATIONG TIPS
=================================
	- When you define a use case, use a name that communicates purpose. it should be clear what the use case refers to by just looking
	  at the name of the use case.

	- Define one atomic behaviour per use case. try not to put more than one specific scenario into a use case because these will make 
	  the use case easier to understand and better suited for their roles.

	- Define the "flow of events clearly". Do it from a perspective of an outsider. The outsider should be able to read the description
	  of the flow of events and understand exactly how the system works or how that specific piece of functionality works.

	- Provide only essential details

	- factor variants. There is a way to factor "common behaviours and variants" when defining use cases. ejm: A system that requires a login
	  will probably require an initial login step for each use case. It is possible that instead of describing the same steps or same sub-steps
	  for each use case , you can factor that out and create a use case that you should then include in your own use cases. (investigar mas sobre esto)


UML BEHAVIORAL DIAGRAMS: SEQUENCE DIAGRAM
===========================================
	- What is a sequence diagram?
	- It is an interaction diagram that emphasizes how objects communicate and the time ordering of the messages between objects.
	- Ver ejemplo en udacity

UML BEHAVIORAL DIAGRAMS: STATE TRANSITION DIAGRAM
===================================================
	- The state transition diagram is defined for each relevant class in the system and basically shows the possible live history
	  of a given class or object. So what does it mean to describe the life history?
	- It means that it describes the possible states of the class as defined by the values of the class attributes.
	- It also describes the events that cause the transition from one state to another.
	- Finally, it describes the actions that result from a state change.
	- Putting all this together we can see how this represents the whole history of the class, from its creations to its destruction.
	- Ver ejemplo en udacity. 
























 
		  
		